Steven Ott Software Developer

Madison, WI · (920) 286-1509 · stevenott@charter.net · stuott.github.io

About

Software developer with two years of experience working on the cardiology application team at Epic Systems, designing and implementing workflows for clinicians at large-scale healthcare systems. Demonstrated ability to create high-quality software solutions that solve complex customer issues while keeping commitments and meeting quarterly release timelines.

Relevant Skills

HTML SASS/CSS JavaScript/TypeScript React .NET/C# Caché C++ Python

Git Visual Studio VS Code Project Management Code/Design Review Testing Procedures

Professional Experience

Software Developer

June 2022 - Present

Epic Systems

Verona, WI

- Investigated and implemented fixes for existing functional issues by collaborating with an interdisciplinary team of developers, testers, and customer-facing roles
- Enhanced workflows for clinicians working in procedural specialties by reducing required clicks and consolidating documentation tools
- Reviewed proposed code changes and designs from other developers to ensure proper code quality and prevent issues in cross-app functionality
- Supported a team of forty developers through a transition from SVN to Git version control by completing additional troubleshooting training and holding daily office hours
- Traveled to customer sites to aid end-users as they installed a new cardiology application as well as gain an understanding of their work environment and challenges

Software Engineering Intern

May 2021 - August 2021

Plexus Corp

Neenah, WI

- Developed software updates for embedded systems used by medical device manufacturers
- Evaluated existing product requirements and created software verification test procedures to provide a reliable quality standard for an integrated system
- Improved development workflows by migrating source code repositories from SVN to Git and creating project-specific virtual environment configurations

Optometric Technician

May 2020 - August 2020

Your Eye Care Team

New Holstein, WI

- Coordinated with a team to efficiently perform comprehensive eye health examinations and provide high-level medical eye care
- Maintained proper HIPAA procedures and security guidelines to safeguard patient confidentiality and sensitive information

Education

Michigan Technological University

September 2018 – May 2022

BS Computer Engineering · 3.93 GPA · Dean's List